Danielle Andrews

Software Engineer / U.S. Marine Corps Veteran

Software engineer with 4+ years of experience in end-to-end full-stack development across startups, mid-sized companies, and open-source projects with HTML, CSS, JavaScript, YAML, a background in mechanical engineering (9+ years) and leadership (6+ years), both GraphQL, Markdown in the military and as an engineer.

EXPERIENCE

Software Engineer at Hack For LA APRIL 2024 - PRESENT

- Refactored GHA workflows using YAML and GraphQL for the website team when the organization migrated from GitHub Projects (classic) to the new Projects, improving workflow efficiency by 30%.
- Updated technical documentation to improve clarity, reducing confusion for new contributors, leading to a 10% reduction in mistakes on Good First Issues and a 5% higher retention rate in new contributors.
- Improved accessibility for the 311-data project by implementing zoom controls for the map that comply with WCAG standards.

Software Engineer at Playpod JUNE 2023 – SEPTEMBER 2023

- Architected the language globalization feature, resulting in a 95% increase in the product's user base.
- Enhanced app functionality by implementing robust error handling, introducing a cache of profile photos for user selection, and incorporating breadcrumbs for seamless navigation, reducing user drop-off rates by 40%.

Software Engineer at Danielle's Consulting JUNE 2020 - PRESENT

- Defined statements of work for a diverse client base that ranges from small to mid-size companies, serving customers and agencies statewide.
- Developed comprehensive end-to-end solutions for client websites, ranging from static to dynamic sites, focusing on accessibility for a wide range of users.
- Guided clients through the entire development process, troubleshot existing site issues, and provided ongoing support as business needs evolved.
- Recent client examples:
- Tahuya River Valley Water District
- The Bridge Workforce Training and Development, LLC
- Other projects:
- Cooler Than You HVAC, My Cook Book Recipe Saver, Hood Canal Stargazers APOD, SpaceBattle!, MyDash Extension, and many more.

Engineering Manager at A&E Conveyor Systems APRIL 2019 – JUNE 2020

- Created and maintained an engineering schedule, resulting in 20% faster project completion.
- Lead engineering projects, using Autodesk Suite, from sales hand-off, through project completion, to customer support.
- Oversaw in-house product fabrication and assembly.
- Managed the mechanical engineering team, while coordinating with internal departments, vendors, and customers, resulting in 95% on-time and in-budget project completion rate.

(770) 355-1281 danielle.andrews.dev@icloud.com danielle-andrews.devdecks.com github.com/DrAcula27 linkedin.com/in/daniellerandrews

Programming Languages

Libraries & Frameworks

Bootstrap, Tailwind CSS, MUI, React, jQuery

Tools & Platforms

MongoDB, AWS S3, PostgreSQL, Node.js, Express.js, Postman, Git, GitHub, Vercel, Render, GoDaddy, VSCode, VirtualBox, JIRA

Design

Canva, Figma, Gimp, Adobe **Express**

Mechanical Engineering

Autodesk Suite, SolidWorks, Tekla Structures, LaTeX

EDUCATION

B. S. Mechanical Engineering

Kennesaw State University

- Honors: Magna Cum Laude, Global Engagement Certification
- Relevant Course: Programming for Engineers (C++)

MILITARY

USMC Veteran

Helicopter Mechanic | Sergeant (E5)

VOLUNTEERING

SciPy Conference 2024

Tacoma, WA

Hood Canal Salmon Enhancement Group

Field Research & Stewardship

INTERESTS

Smart house: home server, pi-hole ad-sink, home assistant; 3D printing; Discworld; Skyrim